Mehrdad moradi Oftadeh

Addison, TX

-Email me on Indeed: http://www.indeed.com/r/Mehrdad-moradi-Oftadeh/58c09a95a34de926

looking for professional career opportunities that utilize my technical experience as well as my education

Willing to relocate: Anywhere, Authorized to work in the US for any employers (I have received a Permanent Resident Card since 2017).

Willing to relocate: Anywhere

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

Work Experience

Electrical Control Technician

Encorewire - McKinney, TX October 2019 to May 2021

- technical knowledge of the operation of AC and DC drives.
- having experience directly involved in troubleshooting and field repair of electrical and electronic systems and equipment.
- understanding of PID and control loops.
- understanding of speed feedback devices theory and operation.
- understanding of Ethernet communications and connections.
- Responsible to troubleshoot and fix electrical equipment.
- Proficient in PLC and HMI systems, including communications drivers and connections, PLC program navigation, and controlled manipulation.
- understanding and demonstrate the processes involved in diagnosing defective components, motors, drives, and electronic components.
- understanding of all electrical components and electronic devices.
- Work with low/medium voltage and high amperage equipment.

Electrical Test Technician

Benning power electronics Inc - Richardson, TX March 2018 to August 2019

Use electrical test equipment to troubleshoot electrical circuitry.

Drill holes and run new wires through industrial panels.

Install switches and control panels.

Use diagnostic equipment to ensure safe and full functionality of installed systems.

Read and interpret blueprints and wiring schematics.

I am totally familiar to do soldering electrical small parts.

I can work with the oscilloscope and electrical measurements (Multimeter, clamp meter).

repair and fix the industrial inverters and converters such as (static by pass) for T-Mobile and at&t.

Electrical Engineer

Iran construction Engineering organization Company - mashhad-Iran May 2015 to December 2016

- Worked in Operation department where area of work included design and planning related activities associated with electric utility building facilities.
- Provided technical support in the resolution of complex power system concerns.
- Planned, drafted, executed, maintained and improved electrical instruments, equipment, facilities, components and systems.
- Examined installations and observed operations to ensure conformance to design and equipment specifications, and provided technical assistance to field personnel in the areas of low medium voltage distribution equipment and low medium voltage motors/generators.

High voltage and power systems engineer

Khorasan Power Engineering Consultant Co (Moniran) - Mashhad-Iran December 2012 to April 2015

- Performed calculations to establish manufacturing installation and construction standards.
- Observed operations ensuring conformance to design and equipment specifications.
- Regularly tested vendor and competitor products to increase organizational offerings.
- Directed installation of electrical components and tested completed work to ensure compliance.

Education

diploma

electrician training program

March 2019

Bachelor's Degree in Electrical Engineering(distribution and transmission networks)

Ferdowsi university of Mashhad

October 2005 to December 2009

Skills

- Maintenance (3 years)
- CAD (1 year)
- Computer networking
- High voltage (5 years)
- Sensors (4 years)
- Hydraulics (1 year)
- Mechanical knowledge (1 year)
- Programmable logic controllers (2 years)
- Test automation (1 year)
- Schematics (5 years)
- Power tools (5 years)
- Blueprint reading (5 years)
- OSHA (3 years)
- power supply (5 years)

- Electrical experience (5 years)
- Autodesk (1 year)
- Low voltage (5 years)
- Calibration (2 years)
- Soldering (1 year)
- C++ (2 years)
- MATLAB (2 years)
- Electrical systems (5 years)
- Electrical engineering (4 years)
- electrical test engineering (4 years)
- PLC (2 years)

Links

http://linkedin.com/in/mehrdad-moradi-power